<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jack Olney</title><link>https://jackolney.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Jack Olney</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jackolney.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Rapid access to health data in the UK</title><link>https://jackolney.github.io/posts/2020-03-06-health-data/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jackolney.github.io/posts/2020-03-06-health-data/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the field of public health, there is a need to access health and healthcare-related data much
faster than ever before.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A pertinent example of this is the current coronavirus outbreak (COVID-19). In early February 2020,
merely days after the first cases were confirmed in the UK, the &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/organisations/department-of-health-and-social-care">Department of Health and Social Care&lt;/a>
along with &lt;a href="https://www.ukri.org/">UK Research &amp;amp; Innovation&lt;/a> announced a £20M investment to
facilitate rapid research on the virus by world-class UK academic and industry experts&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>.
Encouragingly, this announcement was met with great interest across the sector and my hope is this
funding will enable us to ultimately control the current outbreak.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://jackolney.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jackolney.github.io/about/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hello, I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;a href="http://www.imperial.ac.uk/people/jack.olney">Jack&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I manage the &lt;a href="https://www.imperial.ac.uk/business-school/research/health-economics/">Centre for Health Economics &amp;amp; Policy Innovation&lt;/a>
at &lt;a href="https://imperial.ac.uk/business-school/">Imperial College Business School&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am in charge of all aspects of Research Support for the Centre, including:&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="core-management">Core Management&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Provide high level oversight to operational activities of the Centre&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lead the development of all initiatives and strategies to maximise the growth and sustainability
of the Centre, including the development of our vision and mission&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Undertake continuous operational and financial assessments against clear objectives, to maintain
the quality, effectiveness and efficiency of our research&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Engage with senior staff at all levels of the university to ensure the strategic alignment of
our objectives&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Attend and chair key management groups and committees&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Establish and coordinate activities of the Centre&amp;rsquo;s Advisory Board Provide management oversight
on all research projects&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Manage infrastructure and resources necessary for conducting research&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lead on and coordinate grant applications for external funding&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Establish working relationships with data providers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ensure the continuity of contracts, and faciliate the growth and career development of research
staff&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Maintain the financial accountability and sustainability of the Centre Lead the delivery of
communication, dissemination and exploitation plans for all outputs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Utilise technological innovations to enhance the activities and impact of the Centre&amp;rsquo;s research&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Provide a supportive, inclusive and motivating working environment&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Line management of professional and research staff&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Responsibility for all marketing activities, including the website, social media and annual
conference&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="financial-management">Financial Management&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Management of Centre budget and reporting routines&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Leading fund raising efforts with relevant Business School and College offices&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ensuring compliance with all internal, funder-specific and national reporting requirements, audit
requirements, contracts, costing, approvals, procurement and employment&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Overseeing preparation of research content and financial reports as per funder requirements&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Identifying suitable funding opportunities from research councils, charities,
governments, industry and other external bodies for our academics tailored to their research
interests, while facilitating cross-faculty and cross-discipline collaborations on bids&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="information-governance">Information Governance&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>As Information Governance lead for the Centre, ensuring compliance with all appropriate
Information Governance legislation including GDPR, DPA and FoI among others&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In collaboration with the Data Protection Officer, ensuring all IG policies for the Centre are up
to date and all breach reporting procedures are followed&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="research-management">Research Management&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Leading, in collaboration with Centre Faculty, the development of grant and fellowship
applications, including writing content; all administrative matters including costing staff and
resources, ensuring compliance with funder requirements, achieving appropriate sign off; and the
submission of bids&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Leading the management of active Centre research projects, including hiring staff, data
negotiation and acquisition, data storage and processing, data manipulation and technical research
issues, funder compliance, budget planning, communication, event management, dissemination, progress
reports and resolving any project-related issues&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="data-management">Data Management&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Management of the Centre’s data assets, including identifying needs for key datasets; leading
applications for data; establishing relationships with data providers and negotiating access to
data; identifying and ensuring researchers store and process data in an appropriately compliant and
suitable environment for research; obtaining ethics clearance where necessary; managing arrangements
for preserving data security and confidentiality; and ensuring users are compliant with the relevant
data regulations&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="external-relations">External Relations&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Developing links with external organisations and across College, including academic partners in
teaching and research; potential users of the Centre’s work in health systems, government and
relevant industries&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="events">Events&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Management of all Centre events, including conferences, project meetings, dissemination and
networking events&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Promoting activities internally and externally via networks, social networking, online media
and other marketing channels&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B02uVauBTUwhaUR3S2pmeld2WDQ/preview">&lt;em>Curriculum vitae&lt;/em>&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CROI 2017</title><link>https://jackolney.github.io/posts/2017-02-21-croi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 09:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jackolney.github.io/posts/2017-02-21-croi/</guid><description>&lt;p>For the second year in a row, I was invited to speak at the annual &lt;a href="http://www.croiconference.org/">Conference on Retroviruses and Opportunistic Infections (CROI)&lt;/a>. This year the conference was held in one of my favourite cities, Seattle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I spoke about my new web-based modelling tool that enables countries to enter data on their HIV care programmes, estimate the achievement of the &lt;a href="http://www.unaids.org/en/resources/documents/2014/90-90-90">UNAIDS 90-90-90&lt;/a> and prioritise strategies to achieve these goals by the target date of 2020.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Writing a PhD Thesis</title><link>https://jackolney.github.io/posts/2016-11-17-thesis/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 09:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jackolney.github.io/posts/2016-11-17-thesis/</guid><description>&lt;p>Right from the start of my PhD, I was keen to avoid leaving the &amp;ldquo;writing up&amp;rdquo; stage until the last moment. After hearing stories from other students of 24-hour stints in the library and solid weekends spent slaving over their theses in the final months, I figured there must be another way. Sometime during my second year, I devised a plan for writing the thesis:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="for-the-final-year-of-my-phd-i-was-going-to-wake-up-an-hour-earlier-than-usual-and-before-doing-anything-else-write-for-a-solid-couple-of-hours">For the final year of my PhD I was going to wake up an hour earlier than usual, and before doing anything else, write for a solid couple of hours&lt;/h3>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I figured that if I was aiming to submit my thesis in October I had about 10 months, or 40 weeks in order to make a substantial dent in the thesis before having to switch to writing full-time. Excluding weekends, 40 weeks of an hour a day works out at 200 hours.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Webfonts in ggplot2</title><link>https://jackolney.github.io/posts/2016-08-15-ggplot2-font/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 09:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jackolney.github.io/posts/2016-08-15-ggplot2-font/</guid><description>&lt;p>Thanks to Hadley&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://github.com/hadley/ggplot2">ggplot2 package&lt;/a>, we are no longer confined to base graphics plots in &lt;a href="https://www.r-project.org/">R&lt;/a>. However, by default all fonts are generated using the &amp;lsquo;Helvetica&amp;rsquo; family. Now this is a great sans serif font, as evidenced by the fact that it is use literally everywhere in everything.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But now that we have these incredible graphical capabilities, and the ability to produce &lt;a href="http://fivethirtyeight.com/features/our-47-weirdest-charts-from-2015/">FiveThirtyEight&lt;/a> quality figures, we should really explore how to enhance our plots further with the use of better fonts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Future Needs for Characterising the HIV Care Cascade</title><link>https://jackolney.github.io/posts/2016-06-21-sacema/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 09:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jackolney.github.io/posts/2016-06-21-sacema/</guid><description>&lt;p>As we progress toward the end of the fourth decade of the HIV epidemic, substantial progress has
been made in reducing the morbidity and mortality of those living with HIV&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, particularly
due to the availability of antiretroviral therapy (ART)&lt;sup id="fnref:3">&lt;a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. However, we must pause, and assess the
current state of the epidemic to understand where limited resources are best utilised. At present,
countries are inadequately prepared to evaluate the prospect of achieving the UNAIDS 90-90-90
targets by 2020, but with further enhancements they could be&lt;sup id="fnref:4">&lt;a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">4&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shiny Progress Bars</title><link>https://jackolney.github.io/posts/2016-04-01-shiny/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 09:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jackolney.github.io/posts/2016-04-01-shiny/</guid><description>&lt;p>Lately, I have been working on developing a friendly shiny app around a mathematical model to enable non-modellers to get to grips with the model, play around and perhaps learn something too. This has really been as much about teaching myself Shiny as it has been about enabling others to interact with models.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://shiny.rstudio.com/">Shiny&lt;/a>, is great package being developed by a handful of developers at RStudio, and it enables anyone to wrap their R code in an HTML front-end that will run on any computer with &lt;a href="https://www.r-project.org/">R&lt;/a> installed, and perhaps most importantly, run on &lt;em>any&lt;/em> computer if deployed to a Linux server running &lt;a href="https://www.rstudio.com/products/shiny/shiny-server2/">ShinyServer&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CROI 2016</title><link>https://jackolney.github.io/posts/2016-03-09-croi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 01:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jackolney.github.io/posts/2016-03-09-croi/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was recently invited to speak at the annual &lt;a href="http://www.croiconference.org/">Conference on Retroviruses and Opportunistic Infections (CROI)&lt;/a>, held this year in Boston. I spoke briefly about some of my work on home-based counselling and testing programmes in western Kenya, particularly with regard to the timing of testing rounds and the scale up of testing programmes to achieve the &lt;a href="http://www.unaids.org/en/resources/documents/2014/90-90-90">UNAIDS 90-90-90&lt;/a> targets by 2020.&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="600" src="http://www.croiwebcasts.org/console/player/29466?mediaType=slideVideo" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen>&lt;/iframe></description></item><item><title>Hubot - a Siri to call my own</title><link>https://jackolney.github.io/posts/2016-01-09-hubot/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2016 09:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jackolney.github.io/posts/2016-01-09-hubot/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have always been interested in how these &lt;em>automated&lt;/em> personal assistants: Siri, Google Now, Cortana etc. actually function. Aside from the speech recognition algorithms, the meaning of the sentence spoken to these programs must be deciphered and then acted upon pretty quickly. &amp;lsquo;Trigger&amp;rsquo; words are clearly important here e.g. &amp;ldquo;give me &lt;strong>directions&lt;/strong> to&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; but the breadth of words that a computer must understand in order to appear &lt;em>human&lt;/em> is simply vast.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Has the Apple Watch improved my fitness?</title><link>https://jackolney.github.io/posts/2015-12-27-apple-watch-health/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2015 09:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jackolney.github.io/posts/2015-12-27-apple-watch-health/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Having owned an Apple Watch since early May, I have built up a substantial amount of data in Apple&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;HealthKit&amp;rsquo;, detailing my daily steps from in excess of a year prior to owning the watch to at least six months after. Therefore, a simple analysis of whether the watch has improved my fitness should be possible. Additionally, I can pull out heart-rate data, stair-flight data, exercise data and map a whole bunch of other interesting stuff.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Interactive Dynamic Models in R</title><link>https://jackolney.github.io/posts/2015-10-16-shiny-cascade/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2015 09:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jackolney.github.io/posts/2015-10-16-shiny-cascade/</guid><description>&lt;p>As part of a new work package I am part of, we needed to develop a dynamic transmission model of HIV care that has a relatively user-friendly interface and that can be run on almost any device.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The initial choice was to go with an Excel spreadsheet, and have a tab hidden in the background with the model running and a whole bunch of simple stuff at the front for the user to interact with. We then wanted this to develop further into something that had parameter &amp;lsquo;sliders&amp;rsquo; so the model was perhaps a little more intuitive.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Apple Pencil</title><link>https://jackolney.github.io/posts/2015-09-09-apple-pencil/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 22:24:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jackolney.github.io/posts/2015-09-09-apple-pencil/</guid><description>&lt;p>Having just watched the latest Apple keynote, I have to admit at being quite impressed at the latest products. Even John Gruber got it wrong! After flat-out claiming there would be no iPadPro announcement, there we have it! But the internet seems rather pre-occupied by the &lt;em>smile&lt;/em> issue, and the &lt;em>pencil&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Regarding the smile, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t care less.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Regarding the pencil, I kind of think is works. Or at least, it&amp;rsquo;s the right time for a stylus.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calling R from a Python instance</title><link>https://jackolney.github.io/posts/2015-07-01-calling-r-from-python/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 09:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jackolney.github.io/posts/2015-07-01-calling-r-from-python/</guid><description>&lt;p>After spending several hours today trying to figure out how to call R from an instance of Python running on the departmental cluster, I figured that I better document this.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-bother">Why bother?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Some background on my problem. I have an individual-based model written in C++ that describes the HIV epidemic in Kenya over time from 1970 to 2036/2056. This model is called through R which supplies a whole bunch of arguments allowing me to simulate a whole bunch of different scenarios. For some time now I have been using Python as a high-level manager for these simulations. I simple stick some python script in a directory, it creates all the directories, writes the R scripts, writes the .bat files and submits the jobs to the cluster.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fun with GoogleDocs API</title><link>https://jackolney.github.io/posts/2015-01-01-fun-with-googledocs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 09:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jackolney.github.io/posts/2015-01-01-fun-with-googledocs/</guid><description>&lt;p>I wanted to document some code for accessing documents (only spreadsheets at the moment) through GoogleDocs using the DIDE cluster and R.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="getting-started">Getting started.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The R code is fairly self explanatory but involves two little tricks to get it to work: (1) manipulating the GoogleDocs URL to export the document as a csv and (2) changes the privilages on the document such that anyone with the link can edit (done under sharing).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thoughts on priority queues in C++</title><link>https://jackolney.github.io/posts/2014-08-25-thoughts-on-priority-queues/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 09:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jackolney.github.io/posts/2014-08-25-thoughts-on-priority-queues/</guid><description>&lt;p>Taking comfort in the fact that I am sure that nobody will read this site except me, I have decided to procrastinate by writing something about a problem, or perhaps I should say challange that I am currently facing. To add some background, I have written an individual-based time-to-event model that describes a series of events that make up HIV care. I have written this model purely in C++, but as it was my first &amp;ldquo;big&amp;rdquo; model and I was still learning C++ at the time, I have since thought about revisiting the source code and changing the fundamentals of the model.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>