<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HIV on Jack Olney</title>
    <link>https://jackolney.github.io/tags/hiv/</link>
    <description>Recent content in HIV on Jack Olney</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 09:41:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jackolney.github.io/tags/hiv/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CROI 2017</title>
      <link>https://jackolney.github.io/posts/2017-02-21-croi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 09:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackolney.github.io/posts/2017-02-21-croi/</guid>
      <description>For the second year in a row, I was invited to speak at the annual Conference on Retroviruses and Opportunistic Infections (CROI). This year the conference was held in one of my favourite cities, Seattle.
I spoke about my new web-based modelling tool that enables countries to enter data on their HIV care programmes, estimate the achievement of the UNAIDS 90-90-90 and prioritise strategies to achieve these goals by the target date of 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future Needs for Characterising the HIV Care Cascade</title>
      <link>https://jackolney.github.io/posts/2016-06-21-sacema/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 09:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackolney.github.io/posts/2016-06-21-sacema/</guid>
      <description>As we progress toward the end of the fourth decade of the HIV epidemic, substantial progress has been made in reducing the morbidity and mortality of those living with HIV12, particularly due to the availability of antiretroviral therapy (ART)3. However, we must pause, and assess the current state of the epidemic to understand where limited resources are best utilised. At present, countries are inadequately prepared to evaluate the prospect of achieving the UNAIDS 90-90-90 targets by 2020, but with further enhancements they could be4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CROI 2016</title>
      <link>https://jackolney.github.io/posts/2016-03-09-croi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 01:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackolney.github.io/posts/2016-03-09-croi/</guid>
      <description>I was recently invited to speak at the annual Conference on Retroviruses and Opportunistic Infections (CROI), held this year in Boston. I spoke briefly about some of my work on home-based counselling and testing programmes in western Kenya, particularly with regard to the timing of testing rounds and the scale up of testing programmes to achieve the UNAIDS 90-90-90 targets by 2020.
 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>